<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<elements>
  <element name="Werewolf" type="Race" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="race-werewolf">
    <description>
      <p class="flavor">A humanoid cursed with lycanthropy, capable of shifting between humanoid, wolf, and hybrid forms.</p>
      <h4>LYCANTHROPIC NATURE</h4>
      <p>Werewolves appear as humans, wolves, or hybrids of both. Their senses and reflexes are enhanced.</p>
      <h4>TRAITS</h4>
      <p><span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Age.</span> Werewolves mature like humans and can live up to 90 years.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Often chaotic.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Size.</span> Medium.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Speed.</span> Base walking speed 30 ft.; in wolf form speed 40 ft.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Keen Hearing and Smell.</span> You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Shapechanger.</span> You can use an action to shift between humanoid, wolf, and hybrid forms. Equipment does not transform automatically (DM discretion).</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Lycanthropic Immunity.</span> You are immune to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks that are not silvered. (Use with DM approval.)</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Bite (Hybrid or Wolf Form Only).</span> Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency bonus to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + Strength modifier piercing damage. Target must succeed on a DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Constitution modifier Constitution save or risk contracting lycanthropy (DM's call).</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Claws (Hybrid Form Only).</span> Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency bonus to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2d4 + Strength modifier slashing damage.</p>
      <p><span class="feature">Multiattack (Hybrid Form Only).</span> You can make two attacks: one with your bite and one with your claws.</p>
    </description>

    <sheet display="false"/>

    <setters>
      <set name="height" modifier="2d10">6'0"</set>
      <set name="weight" modifier="2d12">180 lb.</set>
      <set name="speed">30</set>
      <set name="speed:wolf">40</set>
    </setters>

    <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="2"/>
      <stat name="dexterity" value="1"/>
      <stat name="speed" value="30"/>
      <grant type="Size" id="size-medium"/>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="trait-keen-hearing-smell"/>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="trait-shapechanger"/>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="trait-lycanthropic-immunity"/>
      <grant type="Action" id="action-bite"/>
      <grant type="Action" id="action-claws"/>
      <grant type="Action" id="action-multiattack"/>
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Keen Hearing and Smell" type="Racial Trait" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="trait-keen-hearing-smell">
    <description>
      <p>You have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <element name="Shapechanger" type="Racial Trait" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="trait-shapechanger">
    <description>
      <p>You can use an action to shift between humanoid, wolf, and hybrid forms. Equipment does not transform automatically.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <element name="Lycanthropic Immunity" type="Racial Trait" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="trait-lycanthropic-immunity">
    <description>
      <p>You are immune to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks that are not silvered.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <element name="Bite" type="Action" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="action-bite">
    <description>
      <p>Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency bonus to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1d8 + Strength modifier piercing damage. Target must succeed on a DC 8 + proficiency bonus + Constitution modifier Constitution save or risk contracting lycanthropy (DM's call). Usable in hybrid or wolf form only.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <element name="Claws" type="Action" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="action-claws">
    <description>
      <p>Melee Weapon Attack: Proficiency bonus to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 2d4 + Strength modifier slashing damage. Usable in hybrid form only.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

  <element name="Multiattack" type="Action" source="Khashayar Homebrew" id="action-multiattack">
    <description>
      <p>You can make two attacks: one with your bite and one with your claws. Usable in hybrid form only.</p>
    </description>
  </element>

</elements>
